### **Abishek Venkatesh**

Self Motivated Technologist who is highly passionate and driven towards solving complex problems across multiple domains and emerge as a leader in the sphere of Technology. Multi-talented Analyst specializing in Java Development. Intelligent, insightful and pragmatic with resourceful and detail-oriented approach. Well Versed in Java oriented development for Projects and familiar with all facets of operations.

35-A/11, Vrindavan Society Mumbai, 400601 (+91) 8879201822 abivenky97@gmail.com

#### Skills

- Java
- Spring Boot
- Oracle/MySql RDBMS
- MongoDB NoSQL
- Python

# **Experience**

April 2022 - April 2023

MBO Partners, Remote(Bengaluru) -Integration Java Developer

#### *MBO Portal (04/2022 – 10/2022)*

- As an Integration Developer, worked on building MicroServices for the Portal Project and helped build the entire portal from scratch from the initial ideation phase to the product delivery phase.
- Worked on Java 8, Spring Boot, MicroServices and SQL technology stack.
- Helped write good quality efficient code and also participated effectively in code reviews and wrote code that was efficient.

## Accounts Receivable(AR) (10/2022 – 04/2023)

- As an Integration Developer, worked on building MicroServices for the AR VMS and NON-VMS Projects as well as the AR Transformer Application and helped build the applications from scratch from the initial ideation phase to the product delivery phase.
- Worked on Java 8, Spring Boot, MicroServices and SQL technology stack.
- Helped write good quality efficient code and also participated effectively in code reviews and wrote code that was efficient.

### TIAA, Mumbai -Senior Analyst Developer

### **Bot Center Refactor (08/2018 – 11/2021)**

- As a Back-End Developer for Platform Team Project Bot-Center Refactor, developed Micro-Services in Java 1.8 based Spring Boot and Utilized NoSql based MongoDB for designing and developing Data-Backend tier for our Project. Deployed All Microservices on a containerized Jenkins Openshift Platform Solution.
- Administered all the Database Migration from writing down the migration Scripts to maintaining and deploying them across Dev ST and Prod environments.
- Wrote Automation Scripts for NIghtly Backups.

### Client Transaction Hub (04/2019 - 07/2019)

- As a Team Leader/Manager mentored a group of 4 interns in developing a cache based solution for Client Transaction Hub problem.
- The Caching strategy involving moving from RDBMS based Oracle to NOSql based MongoDB reduced fetched time from 30 secs to 5 mins worst case down to
  - 1.3 secs to 5 secs worst case which was a drastic improvement in performance.
- Replaced the SOAP UI Service with Rest Service for better access through multiple services.
- Used Spring Boot, Java 1.8, MongoDB for developing the Service

 Performed system analysis, documentation, testing, implementation and user support for platform transitions.

July 2017- March 2018

## RAIT MU, Mumbai - Student Developer

### VR Maps (07/2017 - 03/2018)

- As a Student, developed VR Maps a VR based Solution that provides 360 degrees walkthrough of the whole infrastructure where we set it up.
- Used MongoDB, Express.JS, Angular, Node.js for developing a full fledged VR solution for providing end to end walkthrough across all areas in the college infrastructure.
- Collaborated with other developers to identify and alleviate software errors and inefficiencies.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement.
- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects.
- Walked clients and internal staff through troubleshooting steps to resolve common software issues.

#### Education

June 2014 - June 2018

#### RAIT, Mumbai University - B.E - IT

- 1. Completed my BE in IT successfully with 8.57/10 CGPA
- 2. Recipient of Tata Scholarship Award for year 2017-18

#### **Certificates**

- 1. OCPJP
- 2. Python Programming

### Ε

# **Awards**

Awarded RAIT/TATA's academic excellence award and scholarship for securing second rank in college in third year 2015-16.

Secured Silver Medal in Hackerrank during Week Of Code Contest Held in April 2017